mottandbow.com 2019-03-10

# Privacy Policy

###  Privacy Policy 

Welcome to Mott & Bow. 

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the manner in which Mott & Bow (the “Company”, “we”, “our”, “us” and similar terms) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (a “user”, as well as “you”, “your” and similar terms) of our websites, including www.mottandbow.com and our online store (the “Website”). We refer to all of the services and functionalities that we provide—including through our Website—as our “Services.”  
Our Privacy Policy is incorporated as part of our Terms of Use, available at https://www.mottandbow.com/terms-of-use/ (the “Terms of Use”). Please read this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use carefully before using our Website or receiving our Services, and read them again when we notify you of changes to the Privacy Policy that may be made from time to time. By using the Website and receiving Services, you agree to the provisions of this Privacy Policy. 

## If you do not want to be bound by our Privacy Policy, please do not use our Website or Services.

In order to make operate the Website and to provide our Services, we use information we collect to: 

  * Help you find the most relevant products for you by customizing our Services to optimize your experience; 
  * Keep you connected with the Company across the Internet and update you with related Company news and information, if you allow us to do so; 
  * Put you in touch with the right people and address your questions, and 
  * Optimize the information we share with other parties to help us provide the Services to you.

## What is Covered in This Privacy Policy?

This Privacy Policy addresses: 

  * What personally identifiable information does the Company collect? 
  * How does the Company use personally identifiable information?
  * With whom may the Company share personally identifiable information?
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of personally identifiable information?
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of personally identifiable information under the Company’s control?
  * How can users correct any inaccuracies in their personally identifiable information maintained by the Company?

## Summary

The Company may share personally identifiable information about our customers with those within our team that have custodial responsibilities for customer data and with third-parties with whom we contract to help us provide Services. Those within our team that have custodial responsibilities for customer data are limited to only the access that is required for the proper maintenance and care of customer data. Those third parties that we share information may, at their discretion, provide you with the ability to opt-out from communications with them.

Any intentional misuse of customer data by a team member will result in sanctions, up to and including termination of employment. Misuse includes sharing data with anyone outside our company, unnecessary or inappropriate access to or replication of data, and inappropriate deletion or manipulation of data. 

## To Whom Does This Policy Apply?

This Privacy Policy applies to everyone who uses our Website or Services, but sometimes we direct parts of it toward particular groups of users. “Users” are everyone who uses our Website or Services. 

## What Information Do We Collect, Where Do We Get It, How Is It Used?

_We Collect Some Information From All Visitors to Our Website_

: Like many online services, we use technologies like session and persistent cookies, web beacons (tiny image files on web pages that communicate information about the page viewer to the beacon owner), log data, and third-party analytics services to collect and analyze information about all users of our Website or Services. This may include things like users’ search preferences, interaction with ads on our Website, location, and phone numbers or email addresses for matching purposes conducted anonymously through technology or advertising partners.

Our servers automatically record information (“Log Data”) created by your use of the Website or Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device, search terms, and cookie information. We receive Log Data when you interact with our Services, for example, when you visit our Website, sign into our Services, or interact with our email notifications. We use Log Data to provide our Services and to measure, customize, and improve them collect and use in the aggregate.

Cookies are small data files that we transfer to your computer. We use “session” cookies to keep you logged in while you use our Services, to better understand how you interact with our Services, and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic information on our Services. We use “persistent” cookies to recognize you each time you return to our Services. We use this persistent cookie to remember your preferences and, if you create an account, to make your user experience consistent after you register.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your settings or use third-party tools to refuse cookies or prompt you before accepting cookies from the websites you visit. You can also use your browser settings or other tools to delete cookies you already have. Please be aware that some parts of our Services may not work for you if you disable cookies.

 _Information We Collect from Users with Mott & Bow Accounts_

: When using our Services, you have the option to create an account or register using your login credentials from one of your third-party services accounts such using Facebook (your “Connected Account”). If you use a Connected Account, we may access and collect your name and email address and other personal information that your privacy settings on the Connected Account permit us to access. If you choose to create an account through the Website, we ask you to provide us with some limited personal information like your name and email address. We may use this information to contact you or share with third parties who may contact you about the services on our Website in which you have expressed interest, or to suggest the Company or other tools and services. If your browser permits the use of cookies, we will collect and store additional information using persistent cookies, as described above, and associate it with your account even if you are logged out. 

## User Profile

We store personally identifiable information that we collect, and log files to create a profile of our users. User profiles help us tailor visits to our Website and to direct pertinent, approved marketing promotions. 

## User Payment Information

When users purchase services on the Website, they may provide payment information (such as payment card number and expiration date). This information is used for one-time and recurring billing purposes according to the type of product ordered and the terms pertaining thereto, and to fulfill users’ orders. If we (or our payment processor) have trouble processing an order, personal information is used to contact the user. Payment card information is sent in encrypted format, as more fully detailed below (see “Security” below) and is used only to send to our payment card processor, for the purposes of collecting payment for Services rendered or to be rendered. We never make this information visible to anyone other than our payment card processor and never communicate it over a non-encrypted connection. The full payment card number is never seen by anyone inside our company, once entered and submitted, except by the payment card processor for the purposes of authorizing, clearing and reversing charges to your payment card. 

## How We Share Your Information

_Personally Identifiable Information_

: We will only share your personally identifiable information according to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

 _Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

: In order to provide and improve our Services and to share relevant ads with you, we use and disclose to our advertising and analytics partners non-personally identifiable information that we collect, including cookie data, some log data, and mobile data. 

_User-Generated Content_

: If you use our user-generated content services, like posting a question, answer or product review on this Website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums or anywhere on the Website.

We may post user content, including testimonials and reviews, on our Website. Some of it may contain personally identifiable information. 

## Protecting Ourselves and Our Users

We may release personal information when we believe that doing so is appropriate to comply with a legitimate law, regulation, or legal request; to enforce or apply our policies; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our rights or property; to protect the safety of our users; to address fraud, security, or technical issues; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay. 

## Operational Procedures

Our operational procedures to provide data security and privacy including the following: 

  * Limiting the number of people within our firm and business partner relationships that have access to detailed information about our customers and members. Those who are granted access to perform their work responsibilities are trained on and agree to this policy.
  * We review our business partners, such as developers, data and application hosting providers, payment card processors, and application distributors and their data security and policies to ensure that they that align with our positions on data security and privacy.
  * Internal procedures and practices are followed to protect our customer’s data, such as data encryption, complex password definition (with periodic revision and controlled access), and in some cases dual authentication requirements prior to data access.
  * Written agreements (physical or electronic signature) will be secured from customers and sponsor companies before information about that customer is shared within our system.
  * We reserve the right to market directly to members of our user community. 

## User Communications

When you send email or other communications to the Company, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our Services. We may use your email address to communicate with you about services you offer or receive, or other business purposes. 

## Surveys

From time-to-time our Website may request information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of the Website and/or the Services and may be shared with the same types of service providers described in the Summary above. 

## Supplementation of Information

In order for the Website to properly function, it is necessary for us to supplement personally identifiable information we collect with information from certain third party sources, including Google Analytics and our payment card processor. You can opt-out of the Google Analytics Advertising Features you use, including through Ads Settings, Ad Settings for mobile apps, or other available means. You may wish to consider Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web, which can be found at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/. We may use third party services to process our users’ payment card transactions. 

## Additional Information Use

In addition to the above, we may use personally identifiable information we collect from you and your computer to: 

  * Provide, maintain, protect, and improve our Services (including advertising services) and develop new services; and
  * Protect the rights or property of the Company or our users.

## What Information Do We Disclose?

## Aggregate Information (non-personally identifying)

We share aggregated demographic and security vulnerability information with our users, partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

We may share personally identifiable information from your profile with third parties, including but not limited to the following: 

  * Such information is shared following receipt of a specific request and/or permission from users;
  * Such information is shared with affiliated companies and/or potential investors (in any form of business transaction, including purchase or merger) pursuant to an agreement which contains reasonable confidentiality arrangements;
  * Such information is shared with contractors who work with us (in order to facilitate our business) pursuant to an agreement which contains reasonably confidentiality arrangements;
  * Such information is shared in order to comply with or in accordance with any applicable law and/or court orders and/or in order to prevent suspected illegal acts, frauds, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law; 
  * Such information is shared in order to help the Company defend against claims and/or establish or exercise any legal right that the Company may have;
  * Such information is shared in order to help the Company prevent violations of the Company’s Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy or to otherwise protect the rights, property, or safety of the Company, or others, including exchanging information with third parties for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## General Matters

_Company Emails_

: You can control whether you receive the Company’s emails by following the instructions at the end of each email we send. 

_Third-Party Websites_

: This Privacy Policy applies to the Company Services only. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as search results, sites that include the Company applications, products or services, or links from within our various Services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.

Our Website may contain links to other websites or mobile applications. When you click on one of these links, you are navigating to another website. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. We do not accept liability for misuse of any information by any website controller to which we may link. We also do not have any responsibility of liability for the content on websites that use the Company Search functionality. 

## Business Transitions

Information about our users and our Website (including the online store) is a business asset of the Company. Consequently, information about our users, including personal information, might be among the assets transferred or disclosed as part of any merger or acquisition, creation of a separate business to provide the Website (or an element thereof), our Services or fulfill products, sale or pledge of company assets as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the Company. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

## Customer Services Communications

We communicate with users on a regular basis via email to provide requested Services, offers, or information. In regards to issues relating to their account, we reply via email or phone. 

## Security

The Company takes reasonable measures in order to safeguard users’ personally identifiable information.

Payment information (such as payment card number) and information about the security vulnerability of users’ websites is protected, by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the aforementioned information when viewed online.

While on a secured page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Firefox, Safari and Chrome becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just surfing.

In addition, we limit access to personally identifiable information to employees who we believe reasonably need to receive such information to provide our Services or in order to do their jobs and take other precautions we deem reasonable to protect the security of users’ personally identifiable information.

However, users should be aware that we cannot fully guarantee the security of their personally identifiable information. As in many computer systems, internet applications and software programs, unauthorized use, failure of hardware or software, etc. may be injuriousness to the confidentiality of users’ personally identifiable information.

If users have any questions about security, please contact us at help@mottandbow.com. 

## Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes, or if a user no longer desires our Services, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can be done by emailing our customer support through help@mottandbow.com. 

When a request for user deletion is received, we will make all reasonable efforts to purge said data from our systems. However, due to the nature of our service, some information may not be fully removed due to backups or archived copies. Nor can information that has already been shared be retrieved/destroyed. 

## Policy Changes

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any change in how we use your personal information we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

## International Site Visitors

This Website is operated in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information the Company collects, including personal information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located. Your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. U.S. law may not provide the degree of protection for personal information that is available in other countries. the Company takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely, including entering into appropriate data transfer agreements. By using the Website or providing the Company with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including personal information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to such transfer, you may not use this Website. 

## Use of Anonymous Information

We may use Anonymous Information (as defined below), or disclose it to third party service providers, to provide and improve the Website and our Services. We may also disclose Anonymous Information (with or without compensation) to third parties, including advertisers and partners, for purposes including, but not limited to, targeting advertisements. “Anonymous Information” means information which does not enable identification of an individual user, such as aggregated information about use of the Website. 

We utilize Facebook’s Lookalike Audiences service to advertise to Facebook users who are not existing customers of the Company and who may be interested in our products. Using an encryption method called “hashing”, we may de-identify your personally identifiable information from your profile and share the hashed, de-identified information with Facebook. Facebook only receives the de-identified data we provide them and these hashed values cannot be used to re-identify our users. Facebook compares our hashed values with hashed versions of their own user information to determine which Facebook will receive advertisements from us. 

## Children’s Privacy 

The Website is neither directed to nor structured to attract children under the age of 13 years. Accordingly, we do not intend to collect personal information from anyone we know to be under 13 years of age. We will direct potential users under 13 years of age not to use the Website . If we learn that personal information of persons less than 13 years of age has been collected without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. To make such a request, or if there are any questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy for the Website or its implementation, please contact us at help@mottandbow.com. 

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Notice 

On September 27, 2013, California enacted A.B. 370, amending the California Online Privacy Protection Act to require website operators like us to disclose how we respond to “Do Not Track Signals”; and whether third parties collect personally identifiable information about users when they visit us. 

We may track users over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising. In addition, some third party sites also track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, you may to set the Do Not Track Signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to help@mottandbow.com. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year. 

## Contact Information 

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, information use, collection, or security please contact us at please contact us at:  
Mott & Bow, Inc.  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
help@mottandbow.com  
Effective Date of Policy: November 20, 2017
